one thing that many Traders struggle
with when trading supply and demand or
smart money Concepts is finding the
right Zone to buy or sell from sometimes
in trending markets price action is
going to form multiple Supply or demand
zones and you're not going to be sure
which one you should focus on failing to
know which zones to focus on and which
zones to ignore leads to a lot of
avoidable losses because Traders will
try and execute from the wrong zone or
even worse from every Zone this can
cause two three or sometimes even more
losses before you actually get it right
and that is not a situation that we want
to get into so how do you actually
identify which is the best Zone to buy
from that's what I'm going to help you
with here today we're going to be
talking through four primary points to
help you perfectly select the zones you
should be focusing on and the zones that
you should be ignoring thought number
one is a Zone efficient inefficiency or
efficiency in a market generally refers
to whether a Zone has been retested or
not a couple examples efficient markets
look like this where all zones have been
retested and inefficient markets look
like this where zones are left without
retests I I see some people trying to
trade out of Supply or demand zones that
have already been retested by Wicks or
full bodies these zones are low
probability why because any buying or
selling orders at these levels have
already been met the orders have been
filled it's the areas with
inefficiencies or imbalances that are
likely to be filled and likely to give
the best reactions because the buying or
selling orders inside of these zones are
still waiting for a fill so the first
step I have for you when it comes to
choosing zones is to focus on the
imbalanced zones to identify an
imbalanced Zone we are simply looking
for Supply or demand zones that have
caused a big move that haven't yet been
filled so we don't want to see any Wix
bodies or anything else trading back
into that zone example these zones are
imbalanced this one is not but sometimes
you're going to see multiple imbalanced
zones so that leads me on to the second
point point number two extreme zones so
in a price move like this which is quite
a common sight we are left with multiple
imbalanced zones in these instances we
have more than one possible point to
trade from which can get a bit tricky
but as a general rule that will treat
you well imbalance extreme zones hold a
lot of weight an extreme zone is simply
a term for the furthest imbalance Zone
from Price within the current leg of
movement so these are standard zones and
this is an extreme Zone in situations
with multiple imbalance zones it's very
likely and very possible the market is
going to come and trade into the low
Zone because we still have imbalance and
inefficiency to fill now this isn't
going to happen every single time and to
combat that we can approach from two
angles buy or sell limits at the extreme
zones and a focus on confirmation
entries at any of zones in the move a
confirmation entry for me just looks
like this where we wait for price to
meet our Zone and then look for a shift
in the smaller trend from lower lows and
lower highs into higher highs higher
lows then we know the small Trend agrees
with the big Trend and our probability
and likelihood of winning goes up a lot
so I tend to prefer extreme zones for my
buy or sells especially if I'm using a
limit order because it greatly increases
your risk versus reward and also
increases the likelihood that the trade
wins remember though trading is a
probability-based industry and sometimes
by focusing only on extr exam zones you
will miss trades that's the nature of
the game and that's where the
confirmation entries come in handy the
third thought is the strength of the
impulse in a trend we have Corrections
and impulses the impulse moves are the
large movements in line with the trend
and the corrections are these little
pullbacks against the trend if a Zone
has formed a strong impulse so a
movement something like this that is
going to be a high probability Zone to
buy from if however a Zone has formed a
very slow choppy bit of price action on
the way up but then we come in and we
form a strong impulse Zone like this
then the second zone is going to be the
one with the higher probability and
while this does somewhat contradict the
previous point on Extreme zones the
simple tip I can give you to take
advantage of this thought is to focus on
the strong impulses when they are the
cause of the break of structure so in
this example of a trade I took a while
back we see there are open imbalances
below but they are weaker zones because
the moves they caused are slow choppy
and all inside of the previous structure
move then we have a strong impulse and
this impulse breaks the trend into new
highs so while this isn't exactly the
extreme Zone it's definitely the Zone
where the most buying pressure came from
therefore being the Zone with the most
interest and the final pointer is does
your Zone exist on the higher time frame
depending on how long you've been
trading by now you might already know
that the higher time frames generally
provide the more accurate setups why
less falce moves and less intermittent
noise High time frames show price action
averaged out low time frames show every
little intricacy of the buying and
selling that takes place within so a
mistake that Traders make is looking too
low if you're looking at a trend that is
visible on the 4-Hour time frame but
you're only looking at the 5 or 15
minutes zones or trades then you might
be missing important information take
this trade for example we can clearly
see here that there are a bunch of small
zones and now we are left wondering
which zone is the right one to buy from
well if we just jump up to the 4-Hour
time frame we'll actually see that only
one of the zones sits within a major
area so because the high time frame
gives a clearer picture we could put our
focus on this Zone as the highest
probability point to trade from this
simplifies the trade down to one clear
Zone cuts out a lot of silly losses and
gives us a very high probability point
to execute from increasing the
likelihood that we win on this trade and
therefore if we do it enough increasing
our Baseline win loss ratio over time
all in all the key points to focus on
are IM balances extreme zones momentum
or the strength of impulse and using the
higher time frames to determine whether
a zone is high probability or not if you
put these points into action you'll be
able to trade with more clarity avoid
silly little losses and catch higher
reward higher probability traits and if
you enjoyed this video and want to learn
more head to the link in the description
to enroll in my free trading course
that's all from me I'll catch you in the
next
video